

EMAIL

thomas@thomaswicker.com

URLS

www.thomaswicker.com www.xiri.io behance.net/thomaswicker

SKILLS

sass/less/css3 javascript angular react/react native ruby/ruby on rails php wordpress command line git/github/svn user interface | UI user experience | UX prototyping | invision | flinto sketch

OBJECTIVE

Hi I'm Thomas, I make cool things for the interwebs. I am proud to define myself as a UI/UX and Senior Front End Developer. I have over 15 years of hands-on work experience in UI/UX design, rapid prototyping and responsive/responsible front-end development. I am a unique developer as I have a diverse background in development & UI/UX as well as a deep underlying core of fine art and graphic design principles.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PRINCIPAL UX ENGINEER

DrillingInfo | June 2016 - Current

Currently building a suite of AngularJS apps that focus on creating simple and intuitive interfaces for our clients to more easily consume and understand the complex data set within the oil field services industry. Working primarily with AngularJS, LESS, HAML, Highcharts and D3.

Key part of small team building out new native iOS and Android apps to better serve the global DI client base.

Leading the effort with management and others to build out a dedicated UI/UX department within Drilling Info to better focus on the customer experience and how to improve overall usability for the customer.

Pioneering a new Living Styleguide for all DI applications which serves as the single source of truth for all designers/developers/vendors when working with the DI brand in both print and digital applications.

SENIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER

Oppenheimer Funds | August 2014 - June 2016

Working in a large Rails app built on stack of MongoDB, HAML, SASS, Zurb Foundations, Javascript and AngularJS.

Collaborating with a large team of 20+ devs on sites with millions of unique visitors.

Key part of the Oppenheimer team that within one year developed and launched a new Investor responsive app, a new Advisor mobile app, and a custom web app built for Oppenheimer's high net worth clients with portfolios of 20+ million.

Worked with UI team to pioneer a custom Rails/SASS component framework which is now the underlying architecture behind all Oppenheimer apps.

Utilizing Agile and Kanban methodologies to manage workflows with large teams.

REFERENCES

Thomas is an extremely gifted and creative individual. If you are looking for a quality designer or general marketing professional you cannot go wrong by adding him to your team. Thomas is a highly productive, intelligent, and flexible person who will help raise the quality of any team he is a part of.

CHRISTOPHER ARON AT&T Mobility

Thomas is a detail oriented designer with great imagination. He is responsible for the majority of our custom CRM system look and feel redo and manages the UI/UX for just about every front end project here at Cricket. His designs are clean, mirrors what the customer wants and delivered on time. Thomas is such a valuable member of our contracting team that we are bringing him on full time here at Cricket. I would highly recommend Thomas for any UI/UX work.

RICHARD COOK Cricket Communications

Thomas is one of those frontend developers that every team hopes to have. He is artistic, can do design, responsive layouts, and UI/ UX work. Additionally he knows javascript, ruby, haml, sass, and git. As a mid-tier developer, it was a pleasure to collaborate with Thomas.

ROB CHRISTIE Oppenheimer Funds

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (continued)

SENIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER

DaVita | March 2014 - August 2015

Worked closely with the BAs, Analysts and the core DaVita business team to develop a custom application for use by DaVita clinics world-wide.

Developed UI/UX focus groups to gather data and analytics to be used in the design/development process.

Created concepts, low fidelity mock-ups, high fidelity wireframes, and UI/UX specifications for the application and development team.

Worked in a stack of HTML5, CSS, SASS, jQuery, Javascript, AngularJS and Microsoft Sharepoint 2013.

Utilized Agile methodologies daily to ensure proper project workflow throughout the SDLC Process within the DaVita core development team.

LEAD UI/UX DEVELOPER (PROJECT LEAD)

AT&T | November 2013 - March 2014

Collaborated with a variety of teams including developers, BAs, SAs and operations to develop rich intuitive interfaces that always kept scalability and usability in mind throughout the project lifecycle.

Leveraged HTML, SASS, jQuery/Javascript and MVC frameworks to design/develop and maintain complex user interfaces and responsive solutions for a variety of internal and external apps at AT&T.

Utilized methodologies such as Agile and Kanban to help with team collaboration.

Project lead on design and development of a new tablet UI for AT&T's Point of Sale Systems and account management application used in stores nationwide.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER III

Cricket Communications | July 2013 - November 2013

Producing low/high fidelity mock-ups, wireframes, and UI specifications as needed to assist the business team with developing new application enhancements.

Collaborating with a variety of teams including developers, BAs, SAs and operations to develop strategies for rich intuitive interfaces that always keep scalability and usability in mind throughout the project lifecycle.

Leveraging HTML, CSS, jQuery/Javascript, Adobe Creative Suite and other related technologies to design/develop and maintain complex user interfaces and responsive solutions for a variety of internal and external applications at Cricket.

REFERENCES

Thomas is truly a worker that loves his craft. I've seen him work harder than those hungry first year career employees, despite the fact that he has nothing to prove. Also, this anecdote is not a story of him taking on extra work, it is him loving to learn new things in his own time.

His position at Oppenheimer Funds was front end but he loved to take on new challenges such as the VPN server he set up at home or his personal website fully built on Ruby on Rails. I would highly recommend him in any role knowing fully that he will rise to the occasion, and enjoy every moment of it.

CODY PALMER

Pivotal Labs

EDUCATION

ART INSTITUTE OF CO

B.A. in Web Design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (continued)

UI/UX DESIGNER & CONSULTANT

The Regis Company | May 2013 - October 2013

Captured details of business requirements via storyboards/prototypes and produced graphics and visuals for consumption by the development team.

Provided guidance on usability enhancements and pioneered improvements to functionality of multiple eLearning applications for CDOT, Ford, McDonalds and many others.

Mentored and provided guidance to Instructional Designers as needed.

Collaborated with teams of other designers, developers, and management to deliver visual assets for use in a variety of eLearning projects for Regis's clients throughout the world and in a variety of environments and systems.

UI/UX DEVELOPER & CONSULTANT

RBSI Consulting | October 2012 - February 2013

Contracted for RBSI Consulting on multiple contracts delivering UI/UX solutions and front end development for contract clients.

Developed storyboards, wireframes, low/high fidelity prototypes, and detailed design specifications for the team.

Responsible for designing/developing mobile app UI in both native and web based formats to mirror/support concurrent desktop application functionality.

Translated business requirements into designs working with Product Management, Systems Analysts, Subject Matter Experts, and developers to deliver a suite of apps.

UI/UX DESIGNER/DEVELOPER (PROJECT LEAD)

APEX Systems | July 2011 - July 2013

Designed/developed complex user interfaces and responsive web solutions for a variety of internal/external web applications, mobile applications and responsive websites.

Collaborated with a variety of teams including developers, business analysts and operations.

Created and managed designs through all phases including initial concept, wireframes, low/high fidelity prototypes and final delivery and implementation.

Integrated usability enhancements discovered through research, heuristic evaluations, user acceptance testing and focus groups.